# Ali (Alex) Samari Moghadam

**Full Stack Web Developer** 

Toronto, Ontario

Email: alexsamarim@gmail.com | Cell: (416) 802-7787

Portfolio: alexsamari.netlify.app | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/alex-samari | GitHub: github.com/Alex-Samari

### Summary

A creative full stack developer dedicated to building and optimizing the performance and accessibility of high-impact web applications with user-friendly interfaces. More than a year of experience developing enterprise web applications, CMS solutions and dynamic websites. Constantly learning new skills such as Cloud Computing, Online Marketing and Search Engine Optimization in order to offer better insights into modern problems.

# **Expertise**

• API Management

Front-End Frameworks

Relational Databases

• Responsive Design

Codebase Architecture

Version Control using Git

# **Professional Experience**

#### Artintech Inc. - Toronto, ON

• Full Stack Web Developer (part-time), Nov 2019 to Present

Work on supply-chain-management system (SCMS) to streamline day-to-day supply chain management operations, save time and manage reports. Grant users tailored access levels, menus, user interface, and controls based on their role and authorization. Offer customizable application modules based on client needs and budget.

Technologies: Angular Material v8, .Net Core (C#), MS Entity Framework, SQL Server, Azure DevOps

### Seneca College ITS - Markham, ON

- Full Stack Web Developer (part-time), Sep 2019 to Dec 2019
- Full Stack Web Developer (co-op), Jan 2019 to Aug 2019

Implement fast and secure back-end services with well-structured relational databases. Work collaboratively with UX designers to provide simple, robust and modern front-end interfaces; optimizing user experience, sales and brand positioning. Was hired as a part-time employee after completing a co-op position to oversee the knowledge transfer of previous applications to 8 new employees.

#### **Related Projects & Results**

#### • Fire Protection Services Web Application:

An Interface for Seneca administrators in order to create, update and delete courses and class schedules and for students to view and select courses. Created a user-friendly front-end experience for faculty's ease of use. Managed user profiles with different levels of authority such as admin, super user and student. Implemented a payment system using Moneris, Canada's largest financial technology company.

Technologies: Angular Material v8, Node.js, Microsoft B2C authentication, MSAL Angular, SQL Server

#### • International Student Web Application:

Developed a dynamic web app in collaboration with a team of 9 developers in order to replace the legacy version of Seneca's "International Student Web Application". Simplified the application flow resulting in faster processing times by administrative offices. Worked in an Agile environment with daily scrums, structured tasks and user stories in Microsoft Azure.

**Technologies:** Angular Material v7, NgRx state management, Node.js, Microsoft B2C authentication, MSAL Angular, SQL Server, Azure DevOps, RESTful APIs

## **Personal Projects**

#### Portfolio Website

A portfolio website showcasing my skills and projects in a simple, responsive and easy to navigate interface. Featuring a responsive design that works on many devices including desktops, laptops, tablets and smart phones. Optimized the deployment process to decrease the size and increase the speed of the application. Managed to reach 100% SEO (Search Engine Optimization), 100% Accessibility, 100% Best Practices and 95% Performance ratings based on "Lighthouse" metrics.

Technologies: HTML, SCSS, JavaScript, Parcel.js

#### Employee Management Web Application

A web application designed to manage employee information (such as name, address, etc.) with the ability to add and remove employees and/or departments. Viewers can only see the home page, users can sign-up with an email address and login using their username and password to gain access to the app's functionality.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Express.js, Node.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

#### **Education**

**Computer Programming Diploma, Seneca College -** Toronto, ON Jan 2018 to Jan 2020

#### **Technical Skills**

**Programming Languages** C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript

Database Technologies Oracle, IBM iSeries (DB2), MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL Server

Web Development HTML, CSS, TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js, Angular, React.js,

Java Web, Ajax, jQuery, Bootstrap, RxJS, NgRx, ASP.Net Core, Search Engine Optimization, Netlify, Heroku, Azure DevOps

Miscellaneous Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, MS Office, IBM iSeries

Access for Windows (AS/400), Oracle SQL Developer, NetBeans,

IntelliJ IDEA, WebStorm, Git, GitHub, Linux/Bash